<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notebooks on </title>
    <link>http://www.example.com/notebooks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notebooks on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.example.com/notebooks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Exploration in Earth &amp; Word Movers Distance</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/notebooks/word-movers-distance-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/notebooks/word-movers-distance-exploration/</guid>
      <description>Links Link to Notebook

What&amp;rsquo;s in this notebook? This is the notebook behind my blog post An Exploration in Earth &amp;amp; Word Movers Distance. It&amp;rsquo;s an exploratin into Earth/Word Movers Distance algorithm that includes a there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of great matplotlib plots and some pandas-fu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Model Output Transformations on ROC</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/notebooks/output-transformations-roc-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/notebooks/output-transformations-roc-impact/</guid>
      <description>Links Link to Notebook

What&amp;rsquo;s in this notebook? This is the notebook behind my blog post The Impact of Model Output Transformations on ROC. It contains some seaborn plots, some pandas-fu with method chaining, a simulation of analyzing model results, and some plots with seaborn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colored ROC Curves</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/notebooks/colored-roc-curves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/notebooks/colored-roc-curves/</guid>
      <description>Links Link to Notebook

What&amp;rsquo;s in this notebook? The Receiver Operating Characteristic (ROC) curve is helpful in evaluating model performance, especially since Area Under the Curve (AUC ROC) has a several friendly interpretations. I use ROC curves in evaluating models I have to explain the model performance to non-technical folks. I was reading through Machine Learning: The Art and Science of Algorithms that Make Sense of Data and stumbled upon this nice visual and interpretation of ROC (tied to AUC):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biclustering (with Paul Revere)</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/notebooks/biclustering-with-paul-revere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/notebooks/biclustering-with-paul-revere/</guid>
      <description>Links Link to Notebook

What&amp;rsquo;s in this notebook? Biclustering is an unsupervised learning algorithm that clusters both the rows and columns. This notebook contains a workflow for completing biclustering in a network analysis context as well as a clean export of the data to an excel spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dimension Reduction with TSNE and Bokeh Scatterplot</title>
      <link>http://www.example.com/notebooks/tsne-to-bokeh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.example.com/notebooks/tsne-to-bokeh/</guid>
      <description>Link to Notebook

What&amp;rsquo;s in this notebook? This is a workflow I use often in data exploration. TSNE gives a good representation of high-dimensional data, and Bokeh is helpful in creating a simple interactive plots with contextual info given by colors and tooltips.
This workflow has been extremely helpful for:
 text analytics/NLP tasks if text data is passed through a TfidfVectorizer or similar from scikit-learn understanding word2vec or doc2vec vectors by passing them to TSNE getting an idea of separability in doing prediction / classification by passing the outcome variable to bokeh  This example uses the Australian atheletes data set, which contains 11 numeric variables.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>